Professional Summary

1 Detailed Medical Laboratory Technician with 6.3 years experience performing complex testing in a clinical laboratory setting. 1 Diligent, accurate and reliable with a reputation for completing high quality, complex diagnostic lab procedures in a timely fashion and in accordance with OSHA standards. 1 Quality control of equipment, reagents and procedures 1 Maintains professional patient care and privacy Key Contributions 1 Performed supervisory review of test results and Quality Control. 1 Trained Laboratory students from the Academy of Health Sciences Phase II program and newly assigned personnel in section procedures. 1 Created and updated Standard Operating Procedures (SOP's) for specimen processing in accordance with the guidelines of US Army Standards Health Services Command and Defense medical Information System standards, as well as the accreditation standards of AABB, CAP, JC, FDA, CLIP/CLIA. 1 Extensive experience performing testing and maintenance on Clinitek Advantus, LH500, Acti-Diff, Sysmex (CA-500, XN-10), Rapidpoint 405, Vitros 350, AXSYM, Architect (Plus, 16000, and 8000), Variant, Cellavision, Stago, Iris, Osmometer, and many more. SKILLS 1 Phlebotomy knowledge 1 Data and statistical analysis 1 Blood bank expertise 1 HIPPA compliance 1 Microbiology expertise 1 Sharp critical thinker 1 Immunology background 1 Lab testing and reporting 1 Hematology background 1 Lab equipment maintenance 1 Urinalysis expertise 1 CLIA & OSHA compliance 1 Chemistry expertise 1 Quality Control 1 Coagulation background 1 Professional Patient Care 1 Toxicology knowledge 1 Resilient, Hard-working, Problem Solver 1 Shipping expertise

Licenses

MLS (ASCP) Certification #254443; Expiration date 11/2018

Professional Experience

11/2014 to Current

Medical Laboratory Scientist Pacific Medical Centers

- Performs complex and sophisticated laboratory analysis, evaluate the effects that a patient's physiological conditions have on the results of
 the test performed, confirm test results and provide the physician with the necessary data to determine the presence, extent, cause, and
 treatment of the disease.
- Assumes the responsibility for accurate results.

10/2004 to 08/2010

Medical Laboratory Specialist Bickford Senior Living i1/4 Aberdeen, IA

- 1 Collect and prepare specimens and perform laboratory procedures used in the diagnosis, treatment, and prevention of disease.
- Verify, record, and report lab results on all performed tests.
- Ensure compliance with government requirements, hospital policies and lab procedures, including maintaining the cleanliness of lab equipment, instruments and work area.

07/2003 to 08/2010

U.S. Army

- 1 Ability to mentally process information quickly, strong troubleshooting skills, an exceptional memory for details, a strong work ethic and excellent people skills developed during Army service.
- Recognized by superiors for accuracy, efficiency and reliability.

Education and Training

2014

Bachelor of Science : Biology and Social Science St. Thomas Aquinas College i¹/₄ City , State Biology and Social Science 1 Sigma Zeta National Science & Mathematics Honor Society 1 Dean's List 3.30

l Coursework in Chemistry, Physics, Cellular and Molecular Biology, and Immunology

Associate of Science : Health Sciences Laboratory Technology George Washington University School of Medicine & Health Sciences il/4 State Health Sciences Laboratory Technology

Diploma Academy of Health Sciences i1/4 City, State

Medical Laboratory Specialist Course 1 Phase I: Commandant's List: Academics: Ft. Sam Houston, Tx: Sep. 2003-Apr. 2004 1 Phase II: Clinical Laboratory Training/Phlebotomy Training: Moncrief Army Community Hospital: Ft. Jackson, SC: Apr. 2004-Oct. 2004
Accomplishments

- 1MLS (ASCP) Certification #254443; Expiration date 11/2018 SUPERVISOR PERFORMANCE APPRAISAL 1 "In her current MOS
 as a 68K Medical Laboratory Technician her skill set requires a vast array of knowledge and a keen attention to detail as she performs
 complex medical tests and issues blood products to all departments of the hospital.
- Her attention to detail was so precise that she was selected over her peers to work alone and unsupervised on night shifts, having full run of a high complexity medical lab where her skills were used to their best degree.
- SPC Kearney has an unwavering mature attitude and work ethic that sets her apart from her peer group and senior medical professionals.
- She has a way about people and a constantly positive attitude, no matter what the situation.
- She will excel."-CPT Gerald G.
- Kellar, MS Commanding Lab Officer 1 "She exhibits an unquestionable desire for self-improvement and an exceptional work ethic.
- She has a positive attitude and displays a willingness to go the extra mile to perform any task asked of her.
- She is dedicated and dependable, and has demonstrated outstanding ability to work independently."-MAJ Felix Ortiz, MS Laboratory
 Manager 1 "SPC Kearney is a highly motivated individual who constantly seeks opportunities for professional development and personal

growth.

- She is incredibly intelligent and is an effective communicator.
- She is also a well-organized individual that can manage multiple competing tasks and requirements with ease."- CPT Shawn J.
- Defries, MS MEDDAC Company Commander 1 "SPC Kearney displays a high degree of maturity and dedication.
- At the rank of SPC she is entrusted to run the laboratory's night shift.
- Her bearing and desire for self-improvement are exactly what we need in our officers."- Deaton, Michael A COL, MC Field Grade Hospital Commander.

Skills

Army, Chemistry, Community Hospital, SC, diagnosis, prevention of disease, government, Immunology, laboratory procedures, memory, Molecular Biology, Oct, excellent people skills, Phlebotomy, Physics, policies, troubleshooting